# 大家好 現在我用油煎一下我們這邊的燙皮
Hi everyone! I'm gonna fry some "tang pi" (ground rice chips), a kind of our local snacks.
# 以前用那個沙子炒也可以炒的 現在用那個油炸一下
We baked them in sand in the past. It also works. But now I'm gonna fry them, using oil.
# 更香哦
It smells even better.
# 看一下炸出來是甚麼效果
Let's see how it's gonna look like.
# 肯定很好吃的
It must be very tasty.
# 不要放那麼多 一點點來放 要不然搞不贏啦
Don't put too much. Just a tiny little bit at a time. Otherwise you can't make it.
# 好快呦
It doesn't take long.
# 這個是很小的時候我們最喜歡吃的
This was our most favourite snacks when we were small.
# 放在油鍋裡面 一攪拌 全部都起來了
Put it into the oil, stir it, and it's done.
# 全部倒完啦
All is here now.
# 哎呀 完啦 太多啦
Aya! My God! Too much!
# 可以
Not bad!
# 這個小時候經常在 在家裡放著就月土子餓的時候吃一點
When we were small, we always had, had some of this at home. So we could take some whenever we were hungry.
# 或者有客人來的時候吃一點
Or we could serve it to our guests.
# 像這個 每逢過年過節我們都會做一點這個
It's like, we always make some of this whenever there are festivals or celebrations.
# 我們做的一般就是這種黃色的
The one that me make is usually this kind of yellow one.
# (這個是 蕉芋口) (註︰沒有原字幕，但他說得太清楚了)
This is, Indian shots fla...
# 這個是蕉芋 蕉芋味的
This is Indian shots, Indian shots flavour.
# 這是韭菜味的
And this is leek flavour.
# 有點炸糊了 但沒事
It's a bit burnt, but no worries.
# 嗯~
Um~
# 可以 我們帶點去那個池塘邊 邊釣魚邊吃
Not bad! We're gonna take some to the pond side. It will be our fishing snacks.
# 你看 兄弟家池塘就在那裡 那裡好多魚的哦
Look! My buddy's pond is right over there. There are a lot of fish, you know.
# 你看那個魚 看到沒有 一大堆 全是草魚
Have a look at the fish! See? A big crowd of them. All are grass carps.
# 我搞根草來釣
Let me fetch a piece of grass as bait.
# 應該可以釣的到
I think it should work.
# 搞點這個葉子 這個是紅薯葉哦 這個
Let me take a leaf here. These are sweet potato leaves, this one.
# 在這摘幾片這個葉子就可以了
A couple of leaves here would be enough.
# 很喜歡吃的 這個紅薯葉
They like it very much, I mean sweet potato leaves.
# 你看把這個
Look! I'm putting,
# 葉子
the leaves,
# 捆在這裡
here. Tie them here.
# 勾在這裡就可以釣啦
Hook them here. Then we can start fishing.
# 可以 那個魚在哪裡 扔到它面前
Alright! Where are the fish? I'm gonna throw it to the front of their eyes.
# 你看 在那個魚鈎上徘徊
Look! They're wandering around the hook.
# 走來走去硬是不咬鈎
They're going here and there. But none of them attempt to bite the hook.
# 很好吃的
It's really tasty!
# 紅薯葉哦 你們都最喜歡吃的 我都不吃
It's sweet potato leaf, your most favourite food, not mine.
# 別逼我放水哦
Don't make me drain the pond!
# 太熱啦 等一下 我倒回去
It's too hot. I'll come back, in a while.
# 看它會不會咬
Let me see if they're biting the hook.
# 受不了
I can't stand it.
# 就在旁邊徘徊它都不吃
They're wandering right around the hook. But they don't attempt to eat the leaf.
# 是不它害怕 我們找個地方 涼快的地方待著 待一下
Are they scared? We're gonna find a cooler place, and wait, wait for a while.
# 再過來
I'll be back.
# 咬都不咬 等了兩個小時了
They didn't bite the hook at all. We've been waiting for two hours.
# 吃都不吃
They didn't even eat the leaf.
# 你看 葉子還是新鮮的
Look! The leaf is still as it was.
# 拿抄網來抄它
Let me catch with a catch net.
# 這些魚 鈎也不咬
These fish, they're not biting the hook.
# 水又那麼淺
And the water is so shallow.
# 下去應該能撈的到
Let me go into the pond. I should be able to catch them.
# 誒 魚呢
Ey? Where are the fish?
# 來 好多 你看
This way! A lot! Look!
# 差點翻車
I almost fell.
# 哎呀 全部跑啦 一條不剩
Aya! All run away. Even the last one.
# 踩我一腳
I stepped on something.
# 難搞啊
It's not that simple.
# 今天撈不到啦
We can't catch any today.
# 有沒有送上門來的
Anyone wants to come?
# 有沒有自願的
Any volunteers?
# 叫我弟他們過來 拿多幾個這個抄網 一起下來抓
Let me ask our brothers to come here, with some more, this kind of catch nets. We're gonna catch together here.
# 抓不到 太大的動靜啦 摸的到但是抓不到它
We can't catch any. We moved too much. We could only touch them, but not catch them.
# 打個電話叫他們過來
Let me give them a ring.
# 要不要換地方 換地方
Shall we move to another place? Move to another place.
# 換地方 換地方
Another place, another place.
# 跑啦 跑啦
It has run away.
Yup!
# 這邊這裡還有好多 別管那裡 / 別管那裡啦
Here are still a lot! Don't care about that side.
Forget about that side!
# 中間 中間 / 跑了就跑了
Middle, in the middle!
It has run away, leave if alone.
# 又跑了一條
We miss another one.
# 還有
Still more!
# 跑了 跑了再繼續 還有的
Missed. Missed then go on. There are still more.
# 看一下啊 就在這裡啦 那邊 看有沒有 這裡
Let's see. It's here. There! Any here?
# 搞不到 我去搞點那個網 再來試一下看行不行
It didn't work. I'm gonna get that kind of net and try again. Let's see if it works.
# 就是它跳我們也先不要動
Let's not start moving even if we see it jumping around.
# 直接抓住它
Instead, we just catch it right away.
# 直接去壓一來 壓下來
Press it down right away! Press!
# 別讓它跑
Don't let it run away.
# 抓住沒有
Did you get it?
# 沒抓住 抓到我的手了
No!
It's my hand!
# 繼續
Go on!
# 誒呦 想跑 抓住它 誒 / 跑啦又
Ayo! You wanna run away? Catch it! Ey!
Missed again.
# (沒有 你看XXX就壓下去) (註︰沒有原字幕，但他說得都比較清楚)
No. Just press down whenever you see anything.
# 還有 還有 不要急 / 就跑了兩條
Still more.
Still more. Stay calm.
# (上一句分兩句)
We've only missed two.
# 看一下
Let me see.
# 又空了 沒了沒了
Missed again. No more, no more.
# 放水吧 抽水機抽水機
Drain the pond! Water pump! Water pump!
# 搞到一條 夠了
We got one! It's enough.
# 這條魚就夠大啦
This fish is really big.
# 放在邊上 別跑了
Put it on the side. Don't let it run away.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦 回去把它煮了
Alright! The video ends here. I'm gonna take it back home and cook it.